Now that you've had a chance to try out SageMaker's hyperparameter tuning,
你已经尝试了 SageMaker 的超参数优化功能
let's take a look and see in a little more detail what's happening.
下面详细看看所发生的情况
To follow along inside of the tutorial folder,
要跟着操作 请打开 Tutorials 文件夹
we're going to be working through the Boston Housing,
我们将使用 Boston Housing
XGBoost, hyperparameter tuning, low-level notebook.
XGBoost (Hyperparameter Tuning) - low-level notebook
Of course, the beginning of this notebook is like the beginning of
当然 该 notebook 的开头
the other low-level notebooks in that we first import any modules that we need,
与其他低阶 notebook 一样 我们首先导入所需的模块
download the data, split the data up,
下载数据 拆分数据
upload the results to Amazon S3 and then,
将数据上传到 S3
we train instruct the XGBoost model.
然后训练并构建 XGBoost 模型
In this case however,
但是
we are going to use
这次我们将使用
SageMaker's hyperparameter tuning API to train a bunch of different models.
SageMaker 的超参数优化 API 训练一批不同的模型
To begin with, this looks a lot like the low-level batch transform notebook,
它看起来与低阶批量转换 notebook 很像
in that to start with,
首先
we construct this training parameter dictionary
构建这个训练参数字典
and inside of this dictionary goes a bunch of information,
该字典里有很多信息
such as the role we want the training container to be run as,
例如训练容器的运行角色
which training algorithm we'd like to use.
使用哪个训练算法
Which in our case is going to be XGBoost,
我们将使用 XGBoost
where the data should be saved.
要将数据保存到哪
What remote instance should be used.
应该使用什么远程实例
A stopping condition in case something bad happens and we end
StoppingCondition 可以防止
up with a very lengthy computation,
计算流程变得很长
like for example an accidental infinite loop and then the first difference.
例如不小心出现无限循环 下面说说第一个区别
Rather than specify the hyperparameters for the algorithm that we are going to be using,
我们没有指定要使用的算法的超参数
instead we specify only the static hyperparameters.
而是仅指定静态超参数
That is the hyper parameters that we are not going to
即不使用 SageMaker 的超参数功能
vary using SageMaker's hyperparameter functionality.
改变的超参数
In this case, we're going to leave gamma fixed at four,
我们将 gamma 固定为 4
leave subsampling fixed at 0.8.
将 subsample 固定为 0.8
Since we are trying to determine the median cost of a house it makes
因为我们要预测房价的中位数
sense for our objective to be linear regression of course we don't
所以将 objective 设为线性回归
want that to change and then we'll leave 10 as
我们不会改变这个设置
our early chopping rounds in 200 as the maximum number of iterations of the algorithm.
然后将早停法轮数固定为 10 并将最高迭代次数设为 200
Next, we specify the input data.
接下来指定输入数据
Now, this is again similar to when we constructed just a training job.
与训练作业相似
We described the data we want to use as the training data,
指定训练数据的数据
we say where it is,
指定数据的位置
that it's on S3, that it's CSV data and we do the same thing for validation.
即位于 S3 上 属于 csv 数据 然后为验证过程指定参数
So, in short, this training params object is very similar
这个 training_params 对象与我们
to the training params object we created when making a training job.
在创建训练作业时创建的 training_params 对象很像
The difference is instead of setting hyperparameters,
区别在于我们没有设置超参数
we set only the static hyperparameters.
而是仅设置静态超参数
We'll set the ones that we want to allow a SageMaker to vary a little later on.
稍后将设置允许 SageMaker 更改的超参数
Now, that training program object is used to create
training_params 对象用来创建
the base model that SageMaker will use,
SageMaker 将使用的基本模型
similar to the way that we constructed an estimator object to be
与在高阶方法中创建
used as the base model in the high level approach.
用作基本模型的 estimator 对象的方式相似
To specify the things that are allowed to change,
为了指定允许更改的参数
we need to set up a tuning job.
我们需要设置训练作业
To do that, we first specify the different parameters that we allow to
首先指定允许的不同参数
vary first specifying the continuous parameters with a max value,
指定连续参数的最大值
a min value, and the name of
最小值以及参数名称
the parameter and also specifying the integer parameters again
还要指定整数参数
with a minimum value or a maximum value and the name
包括最小值 最大值
of the parameter that we are allowing SageMaker to vary.
以及允许 SageMaker 更改的参数名称
After that, we specify the total number of models that we want SageMaker to
接着指定模型总数
create for us and the total number of models that should be created in parallel.
以及并行运行的模型总数
Bayesian is the strategy that SageMaker will use to update the modified hyperparameters.
SageMaker 将使用贝叶斯优化方法更新修改的超参数
And lastly, we need to tell SageMaker how to
最后 我们需要告诉 SageMaker
determine when a model is better or worse and we do that by
如何确定模型效果更佳还是更差
saying that a model is better if the validation RMSE is minimal or is smaller.
如果验证均方根误差最小或更小 则模型更佳
So, we have a data structure which describes
我们有了描述基准模型的数据结构
the base model and we have a data structure that describes how the tuner should operate.
以及描述优化器如何运行的数据结构
If we put those together,
如果将二者组合到一起
we can create a hyperparameter tuning job.
就可以创建一个超参数优化作业
As with everything SageMaker related,
与 SageMaker 中的其他作业一样
we need to make sure to name this job and the name needs to be unique.
我们需要命名作业 并且是唯一名称
Now, there is a further constraint on the tuning job name that you should be aware of.
此外 优化作业的名称还有一个限制条件
Most of the job names that we construct are allowed to be up to 63 characters long,
大部分作业名称可以长达 63 个字符
so we have quite a lot of flexibility in the name that we prepend to the timestamp.
所以我们可以选择各种名称并加上时间戳
In the case of a tuning job,
但是对于优化作业来说
the maximum length is 32 characters and
最大长度是 32 个字符
the reason for that is that the tuning job will create a bunch of
原因是优化作业将创建大量训练作业
training jobs and it will automatically assign
它将根据优化作业名称
those training jobs names based on the tuning job name.
自动为这些训练作业分配名称
So, that's just something to keep in mind you might get
请注意这一点
an error if you make the tuning job name too long.
如果优化作业的名称太长 可能会出错
Once we've specified a name,
指定名称后
we can create a hyperparameter tuning job by saying what name we want it to have,
我们就可以创建超参数优化作业了 需要指定作业名称
providing a tuning job configuration that tells SageMaker which hyperparameters
提供优化作业配置 告诉 SageMaker 更改哪些超参数以及更改范围
vary and by how and a training job which describes the Bass Model.
还要指定描述基本模型的训练作业
Of course, SageMaker in addition to creating the job will start running the job,
当然 除了创建作业之外 SageMaker 还将开始运行作业
and like always, it gets done in the background.
和之前一样 作业会在后台运行
So, if we want to have some sort of visual representation,
如果要直观地查看运行进度
we need to use the wait_for_tuning_job method.
我们需要使用 wait_for_tuning_job 方法